# **Alexis Johan A. Avelino Campos**

React Developer | Smart TV Developer | Full-Stack Developer | UI/UX Designer | DevOps (+51) 950041055 <u>avelino.johan@pucp.edu.pe</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexavelinocam/

Lima, Perú (UTC-5)

I'm a Software Engineer with +4 years of experience developing web & mobile applications using React and React Native within an AWS infrastructure. I also have experience in usability testing and User-Centered Design related to Information Systems. I worked in the education, market, casino, and streaming sectors. I was recently working on a redesign process for Paramount + movies and show pages, something challenging and satisfying for me. I would like to have the experience of leading a multicultural group of developers with the same passion as me for usability and new technologies.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Intive

Paramount +— February 2023 - Present

- My main focus is on redesigning the Shows and Movies section, aiming to greatly enhance the user experience.
- I apply unit testing to the components I developed in the Redesign Tasks, allowing better error control, issues were reduced by 70%.
- We follow design patterns and attribute typing, with the current redesign development primarily focusing on TypeScript

#### AMC Plus & IFCFU projects— May 2022 - February 2023

- Redesign of account subscription and movie collection following a Figma design.
- Changed and managed multiple styles and components from legacy projects to get the expected behaviors and updates of some main web layouts.
- Test changes and review code in local, QA, Dev, and Stage environments. Changes were part of multiple repositories since projects had a complex structure.

**Tech Stack:** React, JavaScript, Typescript, Jest & RTL, Smart TV developer Kits, AWS, Git, Confluence, Figma Wargos Technologies

#### **Casino mobile management**— September 2022 - February 2023

- UI design for the customer tracking and earning rates report in Figma. UX was considered in every step made.
- Project structuring and version definition to set the standards for all developers.
- Implemented main reports with different statistic chart frameworks for customer behavior so managers can quickly understand how business is going.

## **CRM improvements**— March 2019 – September 2022

- Redesign the CRM Casino's system with new features. It also allows them to manage events, promotions, and reports. That decreases the number of times administrators call for support by 40%.
- Designed interfaces for new modules in Figma, reducing the number of bugs and asking customers for their requirements.

Tech Stack: React, React Native, Kotlin, Figma, AWS, Git, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Bash

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages: Advanced:** JavaScript, Typescript, Kotlin, HTML,CSS; **Intermediate:** Bash **Frameworks and Tools: Advanced:** React, React Native, AWS, UX/UI, Figma, Usability Tests, Unit Testing; **Intermediate:** Spring Boot; **Basic:** Jest, Cypress.

Database: Advanced: PostgreSQL, MySQL; Intermediate: MongoDB. Agile: SCRUM

#### **EDUCATION**

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú – Lima, Perú. Informatics Engineering. Upper third. July 2015 – July 2022 CERTIFICATIONS

**Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4** – The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. 2020.

**RESTful API with HTTP and JavaScript** – Coursera Project Network. 2020.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

A Systematic Review of UCD Framework Applied to the Redesign of Purchase Order Modules - AVELINO, A. J. A.; CUEVA, R. y PAZ, F. A. (2022). https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-05906-3\_9